A Guide to the Research Files on Colonial Shoes, 1988
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Research Files on Colonial Shoes, 1988.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 93.11
56 items.
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Documentation relating to colonial footwear compiled by Colonial Williamsburg's Historic Trades program for future reference and reproduction. These files are result from a survey of surviving examples of eighteenth-century footwear conducted by Colonial Williamsburg employees in 1988. Each folder within the file, documents a particular shoe examined and includes a sheet giving measurements, materials used, and information regarding the type of stitching and type of lining used. Each folder also includes a survey sheet, tracings of the various pieces used to construct the shoe, and a black and white photo of the shoe.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Shoes--United States--History--18th century.
Contents List
- Man's Turnshoe, England, business manufacture, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:1)
  I.D. No. 0250.
- Woman's shoe, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:2)
  I.D. No. 0440.
- Man's right shoe, ca.1781. (Box-folder 1:3)
  I.D. No. 0533.
- Sole, insole, one (attached) quarter heel lining belonging to one shoe. (Box-folder 1:4)
  2 quarters and latch appear to NOT be related to pattern and leather. I.D. No. 0534.
- Shoe vamp, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:5)
  I.D. No. 0537.
- Vamp. (Box-folder 1:6)
  I.D. No. 0540.
- Man's shoe, vamp only, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:7)
  I.D. No. 0680.
- Object, fine quality, intact not pulled apart. (Box-folder 1:8)
  I.D. No. 0892.
- Man's heel and sole, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:9)
  I.D. No. 0930.
- Man's vamp, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:10)
  I.D. No. 997.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:11)
  I.D. No. 1011.
- Man's shoe, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:12)
  I.D. No. 1013.
- Man's shoe, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:13)
  I.D. No. 1032.
- Sole only. (Box-folder 1:14)
  I.D. No. 1049.
- Two pieces of heel, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:15)
  I.D. No. 1063.
- Rear half of outer sole and heel, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:16)
  I.D. No. 1065.
- Man's turnshoe, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:17)
  I.D. No. 1109.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:18)
  I.D. No. 1123.
- Shoe with overlapping stitching intact right quarter. (Box-folder 1:19)
  I.D. No. 1155.
- Turnshoe, sole and heel, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:20)
  I.D. No. 1211.
- Man's shoe, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:21)
  I.D. No. 1236.
- Man's turnshoe, England, business manufacture, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:22)
  I.D. No. 1266.
- Man's shoe (1/2 sole only), ca.1781. (Box-folder 1:23)
  I.D. No. 1272.
- Man's shoe (sole only). (Box-folder 1:24)
  I.D. No. 1300.
- Sailor's shoe (insole only), England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 1:25)
  I.D. No. 1347.
- Man's shoe, ca.1781. (Box-folder 1:26)
  I.D. No. 1361.
- Pieces of man's shoe, latches, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 1:27)
  I.D. No. 1399.
- Man's work shoe (turnshoe with insole), England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 2:1)
  I.D. No. 1400.
- Man's shoe parts, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:2)
  I.D. No. 1444.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:3)
  I.D. No. 1443.
- Man's shoe parts, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:4)
  I.D. No. 1445.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:5)
  I.D. No. 1404.
- Turnshoe/insole, buckled, clump sole repair, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 2:6)
  I.D. No. 1450.
- Man's shoe, vamp only, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:7)
  I.D. No. 1542.
- Man's shoe parts, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:8)
  I.D. No. 1563.
- Man's shoe, England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:9)
  I.D. No. 1608.
- Man's shoe parts, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:10)
  I.D. No. 1612.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:11)
  I.D. No. 1613.
- Sailor's shoe, insole, turnsole, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:12)
  I.D. No. 1673.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1783. (Box-folder 2:13)
  I.D. No. 1679.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:14)
  I.D. No. 1764.
- Sailor's shoe, piece of heel, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 2:15)
  I.D. No. 1790.
- Man's shoe part (sock linear only), ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:16)
  I.D. No. 1972.
- Sailor's shoe, heel only, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:17)
  I.D. No. 1800.
- Sailor's shoe, 2 quarters only, England, ca.1781 (Box-folder 2:18)
  I.D. No. 1821.
- Man's dress shoe, England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:19)
  I.D. No. 1822.
- Man's shoe, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:20)
  I.D. No. 1824.
- Man's shoe, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:21)
  I.D. No. 1881.
- Man's shoe, England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:22)
  I.D. No. 1882.
- Sailor's turnshoe, heavily patched, England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:23)
  I.D. No. 1848.
- Man's shoe (not dis-assembled), England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:24)
  I.D. No. 1886.
- Man's shoe vamp (fragment only), ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:25)
  I.D. No. 1995.
- Sailor's shoe, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:26)
  I.D. No. 3941.
- Sailor's shoe, welt, England, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:27)
  I.D. No. 3972.
- Sailor's shoe, welt, England, ca. 1781. (Box-folder 2:28)
  I.D. No. 5085. Maker's name is C.H. or H.C.
- Man's shoe, England, business manufacture, ca.1781. (Box-folder 2:29)
  I.D. No. 17495.